Marcos Minond

https://minond.xyz https://github.com/minond

Summary

I am incredibly passionate about computer science and software engineering. Even if money wasn't a concern, I would still be programming. My main areas of expertise and interest are distributed systems, backend systems, and language design and implementation. I also volunteer at the Refugee Education and Training Center of Utah as an organizer and teacher for programming classes where I teach classes and mentor students.

Skills

Scala, Go, Ruby, Python, TypeScript/JavaScript, Elm, bash, Linux, software design and architecture, process automation, continuous integration, distributed systems, observability, planning and project management.

Experience

Software Engineer, Freelance, Minond, LLC

January 2023 - Present

Staff Software Engineer, MX

April 2018 - December 2022

Played an active part in shaping our platform as both an individual contributor and a mentor to individuals and teams designing and developing solutions for a rapidly evolving industry and ecosystem.

- Member of the Enterprise Technical Office group where I dealt with high urgency client requirements and advised in project architecture and problem solving platform-wide.
- Led and owned new initiative to improve our client's developer experience. This included building SDKs for major mobile platforms. Evangelized this team's solutions and enhancements to internal and external parties.
- Technical lead to over a dozen backend and frontend engineers in the design and development of MXinsights, a financial feed product currently serving over 7 million users.

Software Engineer, Freelance, Minond, LLC

May 2017 - April 2018

Helped various companies dismantle and analyze problems, develop and vet new ideas and solutions, and build mission-critical products.

Software Engineer, Tech Lead, Domo, Inc.	December 2014 - May 2017
Software Engineer, Tech Lead, InsideSales.com	January 2014 - November 2014
Software Engineer, DevOps, InsideSales.com	June 2013 - January 2014
Software Engineer, InsideSales.com	January 2012 - June 2013
Implementation Team Member & Manager, InsideSales.com	January 2009 - December 2011

Education

Utah Valley University, BS, Computer Science (Incomplete)

2009 - 2013

Volunteering

Programming Class Organizer & Instructor, Utah Department of Workforce Services

2016 - Present

I organize and teach programming classes for refugees and members of my community.